totaltravel.co.uk 2007-05-02

# Privacy - Total Travel Siteholders

## Privacy

## Privacy and Security Statement

TotalTravel understands that interacting with websites involves a great deal of trust on your part. We respect your trust in us and we are committed to ensuring the security and confidentiality of the personally identifiable information you provide us. 

By visiting totaltravel.co.uk, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Statement.

## What Information do we collect and how do we collect it?

TotalTravel collects personally identifiable information about you that you specifically and voluntarily provide. The information we collect from you allows us to personalise and improve the totaltravel experience. We use the information to handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us, display personalization content, customer reviews and recommend services that might be of interest to you. We also use this information to improve our site, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

## The totaltravel.co.uk Privacy and Security Statement - What information do we collect?

## Information provided by you:

You can decide what personally identifiable information you provide to us.

We will only collect personally identifiable information that you choose to provide. You can choose not to provide certain information. Where possible, we will enable you to select how we will use this information (for example, by choosing to opt-in or opt-out of receiving special promotional offers). 

You may choose to provide us with personally identifiable information if, for example, you: contact us with an enquiry; register on the site, fill out a survey or other form with your personally identifiable information included; request us to provide you with information; enter a competition; post information to public areas of the site or participate in a promotion. 

By providing any personally identifiable information to us, you fully understand and clearly consent to the transfer of such personally identifiable information to, and the collection and processing of such information in, other countries or territories. Any such transfer and processing by us will be in accordance with this privacy policy. 

## Automatically received information

Every computer connected to the Internet is given a domain name and a set of numbers, that serve as that computer's Internet Protocol (‘IP’) . When a visitor requests a page from any Web Site within our network, our Web servers automatically recognize that visitor's domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about you other than the IP address from which you have accessed our Site. We use this information to examine our traffic in aggregate, and for security purposes and to investigate misuse of the network, its users,  
or to cooperate with law enforcement. 

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use ‘cookies’ and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses totaltravel.co.uk. By recognising you, we can provide you with a personalized experience.

## What are cookies?

From time to time, we may send a cookie to your computer. A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other Web sites. Cookies do not damage your system. We use cookies to identify which areas of our network of Web Sites you have visited or customized, so the next time you visit, those pages may be readily accessible. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of your browser. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies, or allow your browser to show you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept these cookies, your experience at our Site and other Web sites may be diminished and some features may not work as intended.

## Information from third party sources

We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information.

## Will we disclose the information we receive to third parties?

Information about our customers is important to us and we do not sell it to others. We share customer information only as described below and with our subsidiaries.   

## Affiliates and third parties

We work closely with our affiliated businesses. These businesses operate sites through TotalTravel and we may provide services or sell products on behalf of these businesses. You can tell when a third party is involved in your transactions and we may share customer information related to those transactions with that third party.   

## Service providers

Information is only provided to third parties that provide services or functions on behalf of totaltravel.co.uk. These service providers require information about you and your travel requirements, in addition to your credit card information, when required to process and confirm your travel reservation. These service providers will disclose information about your travel requirements to hotels, airlines, ferry, train, restaurants, car hire and the like with whom you have made a reservation. This information must be shared with our affiliates and travel suppliers to confirm your reservation and travel preferences. 

Whilst totaltravel.co.uk only offers travel products from reputable companies,we have not placed limitations on these suppliers from using or disclosing your information without your permission. In the circumstances, we would recommend you study the privacy statements of any affiliate or travel supplier with whom you have made reservations through totaltravel.co.uk. Please note, you may be contacted directly by such suppliers to confirm your reservation. 

Although such third party providers may have access to your personally identifiable information for the purposes set out above, they may not use that personally identifiable information for any other purpose and are required to process your information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (as amended). 

## Payments and transactions

We may use your personally identifiable information in order to respond to your queries and requests and to manage transactions such as credit card payments for any goods that you order from us or any of our affiliates and suppliers. 

Your credit card or billing account details are only retained for the purpose of handling that individual transaction. We will only retain this information if you have agreed for us store this information for future transactions you may make through totaltravel.co.uk. 

## Promotions, marketing, e-newsletters

We may use information for internal marketing analysis, for example, to assess trends amongst our consumers or to measure the amount of traffic to our websites. We may also use your personally identifiable information in order to communicate with you about our products and services and those of our subsidiaries, affiliates, and parent  
companies and any of their related businesses. You will be able to choose whether or not to receive such communications when you first provide personally identifiable information to us. We may also share non-personally identifiable information with others, such as advertisers, in aggregate anonymous form, which means that the  
information will not contain any personally identifiable information about you. 

We will not arrange for selected organizations to send you promotional and marketing information without your permission. In the event you give your permission please note that such organizations are carefully selected and will be bound by the terms of this statement.

## Interactive, reviews, bulletin boards, chat rooms

Information you post on or through the public areas of the site is generally accessible to, and may be collected and used by, others and may result in unsolicited messages or other contact from others. Users of the site are encouraged to exercise caution when providing personally identifiable information about themselves in public areas of this site.  

## Sale and transfer

In the event of a sale, merger,consolidation, change in control,transfer of substantial assets,reorganisation or liquidation, we may transfer, sell, or assign to third parties information concerning your relationship with us, including without limitation, personally identifiable information that you provide and other information concerning your relationship with us.

## Legal obligations

We may be required by law to disclose information you have provided in the good-faith belief that such action is required by law or to comply with legal process served on us or to protect and defend our rights or property and our interests or the interests of our customers or users of the site or the public.

## Other businesses we do not control

This site contains links to other web sites outside of our control and who do not operate under this statement. When you click through to these Web sites, this statement no longer applies. We recommend that you read the privacy statements for all third party Web sites. 

Whenever we transfer personally identifiable information to countries outside of the European Economic Area in the course of sharing information as set out above, we will ensure that the information is transferred in accordance with this statement and as permitted by the Data Protection Act 1998.

## Is your information secure?

We are committed to providing you with a secure environment during storage and transmission of your personally identifiable information. 

As with other sites we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input. 

We have created appropriate physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to collect, store and disclosure your personally identifiable information. Although we use the most technologically advanced security systems available, our security providers cannot guarantee against unauthorised access by third parties. 

Security specifications for the technical amongst you:

128bit SSL security   
Open BSD - OpenBSD is thought of by many security professionals to be the most secure UNIX-like operating system as the result of a 10-member  
1.5-year long comprehensive source code security audit. 

Blowfish Algorithm 

Changes to this statement

This statement will change in accordance with the constantly changing face of our business. Such changes will be posted on this page and it is recommended that you should check our website regularly to confirm what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

## Checking your details

Should you wish to check what personally identifiable information we hold about you, amend your information, request that your information be removed or have any queries regarding the above statement, please contact us at [privacy@totaltravel.com](mailto:privacy@totaltravel.com)

© 2000-2006, totaltravel.com, all rights reserved

* * *
